SESAMY MALWENNA

EMAIL: SESAMYMALWENNA@GMAIL.COM | TEL: +44 749 539 8021

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/sesamy-malwenna</u>

SUMMARISED RESUME

Over 10 years of B2C & B2B marketing experience in FMCG, F&B, hospitality, and banking sectors. I have performed in brand management, channel marketing, and marketing consultancy roles across local and international markets. I bring a wealth of experience in personal care, beauty, home care, and food & beverage categories. My track record showcases a strong dedication to data-driven, consumer-centric decision-making, driving profitable growth. Over 5 years of leadership experience adeptly overseeing and nurturing subordinates to achieve collective success.

SKILL SUMMARY

- Crafting and deploying brand marketing campaigns in local and global markets
- Research & data analytics (Kantar, Nielsen, GWI, Euromonitor, Lumina, Anaplan, Power BI)
- Integrate market/consumer trends in business plans
- · Highly proficient in MS Office packages
- Successfully managing networks & stakeholders to deliver innovations (NPD)
- Manage budget & optimize cost to ensure business profitability (P&L management)
- Excellent at crisis management & vitalising the team for higher performance

CAREER EXPERIENCE

MARKETING CONSULTANT - OFF THE RUCK CONSULTANCY

(MAR 2023-PRESENT)

- Evaluating the client's current marketing mix strategies and executions
- Analyzing industry and competitor context
- Identifying gaps in the market and marketing mix
- Collaborating with the clients to unlock market beating, sustained and profitable growth

SENIOR BRAND MANAGER - UNILEVER SRI LANKA LTD

VIM DISHWASH & SURFACE CLEANER (FEB 2022– OCT 2022)

- Led brand marketing plans for Vim Dishwash & Vim Multi Surface Cleaner portfolios
- Managed Innovation, Renovations and Savings projects to deliver profitable growth
- **Collaborated** with internal cross-functional teams, Global Brand Development teams, agencies, consumer research companies, etc. for campaigns, innovations, and market deployment projects
- Conducted regular data-driven & qualitative analysis on consumers, customer, market, industry, and competition to evaluate business performance and identify growth opportunities
- Crafted and deployed effective communications to minimize category degradation during the recession by uncovering actionable consumer insights
- Launched access packs in dishwash liquids & bars to recession proof portfolio
- Led the purpose campaign localization with the global brand development team and global/local agencies
- Led Vim Surface Cleaner portfolio relaunch with formulation, packaging, and portfolio revisions

BRAND MANAGER – UNILEVER SRI LANKA LTD

CLEAR & LIFEBUOY SHAMPOO (OCT 2019– FEB 2022)

- **Re-launched Lifebuoy shampoo** with an improved product mix creating ATL and trade engagement resulting in brand growth across all parameters: Sales, Profit, Equity, etc.
- Managed the marketing mix to establish Lifebuoy as a VFM, BOP brand creating profitable growth
- Implemented **market development strategies** with compelling communication, driving trials and accelerating soap-to-shampoo conversion, resulting in a notable **increase in hair care category penetration**
- Corrected the communication mix on Clear Unisex portfolio after 3 years, resulting in the growth of brand equity parameters and penetration
- Revamped Clear's Instagram and Facebook pages, elevating our brand identity and fostering consumer engagement. This effort was acknowledged and appreciated by the Clear Global Brand Team
- Successfully **launched Clear Men Deep Cleanse** variant with contextualized communication amidst the Covid pandemic, resulting in **double-digit sales growth of Clear Men in 2020**
- Entered Esports with Clear Men and launched a thematic promotion partnering with ROG to create engagement. Double digital sales growth in 2021 amidst Covid and sachet pack format ban crisis
- Supported in **crafting the 3-year category strategy** and brand plans to recover from the sachet pack format ban crisis and ensure profitable growth in both volume and value

ASSISTANT BRAND MANAGER – UNILEVER SRI LANKA LTD

AXE & CLOSEUP (MAY 2018 - OCT 2019)

- Managed Axe and Closeup portfolios, reporting directly to the Oral and Deodorant Category Head
- Successfully **launched Axe "Ticket"**, **the entry price pack** to democratize the fragrance market for all income classes. Carried out launch campaigns across platforms, ATL & BTL
- Supported in crafting the 3-year strategy for Deo Category and Axe brand
- Conducted **consumer research to understand the Sri Lankan fragrance profile** and created the **innovation pipeline** based on opportunities in the Deo & Fragrance category
- Launched Closeup Naturals Range in Oral Care, premiumizing the portfolio
- Launched 2 communication assets short and long form for Closeup. Created brand engagement among youth with relevant and timely insight. (Closeup Break the Barriers "Face it before Facebook")
- Supported in **crafting the 3-year strategy for the Oral Care category** and created the brand plan for Closeup to develop a gel sub-segment by introducing an **access pack to remove the entry price barrier**

MARKETING & COMMUNICATIONS EXECUTIVE - DILMAH CEYLON TEA SERVICES PLC

GLOBAL MARKETS (APR 2016 - MAY 2018)

- Developed and deployed marketing campaigns in global markets (Singapore, Sweden, UAE, etc.)
- Managed websites, social media and apps. Developed and deployed content across platforms
- Operated exhibition stalls in Trade Fairs (e.g.: Gulfood Dubai) to generate business leads
- Initiated and conducted **Sales Training Programs** in multiple countries for distributors and partners
- Managed the marketing and food & beverage menu for the restaurant chain "t-lounge by Dilmah"
- Launched t-lounge outlets in India and Dubai with campaigns including PR and influencer marketing
- Managed Dilmah tea competitions (E.g.: partnership with Global Pastry Chefs Challenge 2018, Bocuse d'Or Challenge Asia Pacific 2018)
- Worked with hospitality businesses across the world to incorporate Dilmah into their menus (E.g.- MC Café Menu in Malaysia, Cafes in Singapore, Accor Hotels, Pullman Hotels, etc.)

OPERATIONS ASSOCIATE FOR CHANNEL MARKETING - UNILEVER SRI LANKA LTD

SRI LANKA & MALDIVES (AUG 2013 – AUG 2015)

- Supported in managing portfolios under the brands Knorr, Hellman's Carte D'or, Astra, Lady's Choice
- Deployed marketing campaigns in Sri Lanka & Maldives targeting hospitality professionals
- Led the Unilever Food Solutions website relaunch optimizing the consumer journey
- Conducted digital & on-ground campaigns to drive traffic to the website
- Launched Knorr Sauces Range with new recipes and product brochures
- Developed training material for the sales team on product knowledge and marketing techniques
- Organized product demonstration workshops to educate hospitality professionals of UFS product range
- Supported in developing and executing **business development plans** with effective **trade & customer promotions** to remain competitive in the market while maintaining profitability

SPECIAL PROJECTS

- Launched the **first digital sampling platform** for Unilever Sri Lanka SMARTPICK & acted as the advisor to replicate the model in South African market
- Launched the **first Personal Care Vending Refill Machine** in Sri Lanka & Unilever South Asia region, as part of the Unilever sustainability agenda
- Launched Lifebuoy Sanitizer Spray as an agile project during the Covid pandemic
- Worked with Dilmah Conservation & MJF Charitable foundation supporting the company's social & sustainability initiatives

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- MSc in Digital Marketing Nottingham Trent University (2023)
- Fundamentals of Digital Marketing & Google Analytics Google Digital Garage (2023)
- Professional Postgraduate Diploma in Marketing Chartered Institute of Marketing (2018)
- Master of Business Administration Cardiff Metropolitan University of the United Kingdom (2016)
- BSc in Mathematics & Chemistry- University of Colombo, Sri Lanka (2013)

REFERENCES